Guide to the U.S. Army and Navy Letters, 1828-1910 MS 149
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
U.S. Army and Navy letters
1828-1910
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Unknown
MS 149
0.25 Linear Feet (43 letters)
This collection contains letters to and from various high-ranking officers of both the U.S. Army and Navy.
Biographical Note
Letters are to and from various high-ranking officers of both the U.S. Army and Navy.
Scope and Contents
While the letters are on a number of different topics, many deal with the Sterling Debenture Corporation and stock offerings in the American Telegraphone Corporation. The corporation was founded in 1903 to manufacture the Telegraphone, a magnetic sound recording device invented by Danish engineer Valdemar Poulson. Although several hundred machines were bought by curious scientists, the product was not a commercial success.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Purchase from Black, manuscripts dealer, October 1961.
Index Terms
Subjects
Military
Document Types
letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Letters, 1828-1910
  - General Thomas Cadwalader to C.F. Mercer, October 14, 1828 (Letter 1)
  - Brigadier-General James W. Forsyth to unknown, March 9, 1896 (Letter 2)
  - Lieutenant-General Nelson A. Miles to Belford, Middlebrook and Co., November 21, 1898 (Letter 3)
  - Lieutenant-General Henry C. Corbin to Alexander Belford, August 8, 1899 (Letter 4)
  - Lieutenant-General Henry C. Corbin to Berton E. Holley, May 23, 1906 (Letter 5)
  - Rear Admiral H.N. Manney to George H. Middlebrook, August 14, 1906 (Letter 6)
  - Lieutenant Commander C.M. Faks to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, September 6, 1906 (Letter 7)
  - Rear Admiral R.D. Evans to Sterling Debenture Corporation, September 8, 1906 (Letter 8)
  - Captain J.E. Pillsbury to USS Maine, c/o Postmaster, New York, N.Y., September 10, 1906 (Letter 9)
  - Brigadier General T.F. Forbes to Treasurer, Sterling Debenture Corporation, September 12, 1906 (Letter 10)
  - Rear Admiral Victor Ludlow to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, September 14, 1906 (Letter 11)
  - Rear Admiral John S. Rogers to Sterling Debenture Corporation, October 3, 1906 (Letter 12)
  - Commander W.S. Benson to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, October 4, 1906 (Letter 13)
  - Commander C.H. Harlow to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, October 9, 1906 (Letter 14)
  - Rear Admiral Francis H. Delano to Sterling Debenture Corporation, October 17, 1906 (Letter 15)
  - Lieutenant Commander H.O. Shibuey (?) to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, October 22, 1906 (Letter 16)
  - Major General Thomas H. Barry to Berton E. Holley, October 30, 1906 (Letter 17)
  - Brigadier General Peter C. Hains to J.B. Chasseand, December 3, 1906 (Letter 18)
  - Rear Admiral Henry Glass to Sterling Debenture Corporation, March 16, 1907 (Letter 19)
  - Brigadier General A.S. Daggett to R.E. Ely, March 16, 1907 (Letter 20)
  - Brigadier General John M. Wilson to Committee on Commerce and Industry, March 21, 1907 (Letter 21)
  - Brigadier General George B. Davis to Robert Erskine Ely, March 28, 1907 (Letter 22)
  - Rear Admiral C.S. Sperry to National Peace Congress, April 3, 1907 (Letter 23)
  - General Alex S. Webb to unknown, April 6, 1907 (Letter 24)
  - John D. Ford to Sterling Debenture Corporation, July 4, 1907 (Letter 25)
  - Rear Admiral William J. Barnette to G.H. Middlebrook, December 10, 1907 (Letter 26)
  - Rear Admiral William J. Barnette to unknown, December 11, 1907 (Letter 27)
  - Brigadier General A.R. Buffington to G.H. Middlebrook, January 18, 1908 (Letter 28)
  - Brigadier General A.G. Hennisee to Sterling Debentures Corporation, May 31, 1908 (Letter 29)
  - Berton E. Holley to the Secretary of War, June 9, 1909 (Letter 30)
  - Rear Admiral J.B. Coghlan to George J. Seabury, October 29, 1908 (Letter 31)
  - Captain (US Army) J.H. Herron to Berton E. Holley, June 12, 1909 (Letter 32)
  - Captain (US Navy) R.F. Mulligan to Berton E. Holley, June 12, 1909 (Letter 33)
  - Rear Admiral Edward S. Barry to Sterling Debenture Corporation, June 12, 1909 (Letter 34)
  - G.H. Middlebrook to Lieutenant General Adna R. Chaffee, June 16, 1909 (Letter 35)
  - G.H. Middlebrook to Major General F.D. Grant, June 18, 1909 (Letter 36)
  - Lieutenant General S.B.M. Young to D.(sic G) H. Middlebrook, June 19,1909 (Letter 37)
  - Captain, USN, Dennie H. Mahan to Sterling Debenture Corporation, August 1, 1909 (Letter 38)
  - Lieutenant General J.C. Bates to G.H. Middlebrook, August 21, 1909 (Letter 39)
  - Rear Admiral Allen V. Reed to Charles B. Seabury, January 17, 1910 (Letter 40)
  - Rear Admiral John Lowe to Rear Admiral H.N. Manney, September 12, (no year) (Letter 41)
  - Rear Admiral Robley D. Evans to W. F. Fleming, October 9, (no year) (Letter 42)
  - Major General Wesley Merritt to unknown, date unknown. (Body of letter missing) (Letter 43)